A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, South Africa UPDATE Series Files FA1548
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts and working files, 1983-1991; 4; 3.46 Cubic Feet 6 LTR size and 2.5 LGL size Hollinger boxes
  - South Africa Update diskette 0026M, 1987 March 27 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - White Politics - Robert Schrire manuscript, 1987 March (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - White Politics - Robert Schrire manuscript, 1987; File contains digital media. Digital media includes one 5 1/4 inch floppy disk. (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - Robert Schrire, 1987 January 26 (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - White Politics - Permissions, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - White Politics - Charts, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - White Politics - Nokwanda Sithole, 1987-1990 (Box 16, Folder 154)
  - White Politics - Mark Swilling, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 155)
  - White Politics - Lisa and Marius: A Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 16, Folder 156)
- Editorial files, 1980-1990; 5; 1.65 Cubic Feet 3.5 LGL size Hollinger boxes
  Series contains a set of materials that the records' creators referred to as editorial files. These editorial files consist of articles, newspaper clippings, reports, and publications that discuss political developments and news in South Africa during the 1980s. One of the files in the series includes a piece of John de St. Jorre's correspondence that suggests that these types of materials were submitted to the South Africa UPDATE Series' editors as background information on the subjects discussed within the series' monographs.
  The writings collected within the editorial files concern topics such as South African international relations, political activism and resistance to Apartheid by South African blacks, economic advancement of some South African blacks and a black middle-class, anti-Apartheid organizations like the African National Congress (ANC) and the United Democratic Front (UDF), anti-Apartheid leaders like Nelson Mandela, Winnie Mandela, Desmond Tutu, Oliver Tambo, and Mangosuthu Buthelezi, political divisions between different anti-Apartheid groups and the call for black unity made by some anti-Apartheid leaders, suspected links between anti-Apartheid groups and communism, proposed government reforms, and advancements toward negotiations to end Apartheid.
  - Africa - General, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Africa - General, 1988-1989 (Box 16, Folder 158)
  - Africa - General, 1985-1987 (Box 16, Folder 159)
  - Angola - Michael Ranneberger, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 160-161)
  - Blacks - General, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 162)
  - Blacks - General, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Blacks - General, 1980-1987 (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Blacks - General, 1985-1987 (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Black Politics, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - Black Politics, 1989 April 23 (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Black Politics, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 168-169)
  - Black Politics, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Black Politics, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 171)
  - Black Politics, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - Black Politics, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 173-174)
  - Black Politics, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Black Politics, 1986-1987 (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Black Politics, 1983-1985 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Black Politics, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 178)
  - Black Politics - Mangosuthu Buthelezi, 1988 April 28 (Box 19, Folder 179)
  - Black Politics - Mangosuthu Buthelezi, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Black Politics - Mangosuthu Buthelezi, 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 181)
  - Black Politics - Mangosuthu Buthelezi, 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 182-183)
  - Black Politics - Langa township, South Africa, 1985-1986 (Box 19, Folder 184)
  - Black Politics - Winnie Mandela, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 185)